Guide to the Donald Gordon Papers, 1900-1988 UA.90.F46
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, I.
  - Inventory of Kirchner Works, 1.
    - Two Against the World (Das Paar vor den Menschen), 765, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Standing Nude Before Open Door (Weiblicher Akt vor offner Tür), 766, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Modern Bohemia (Moderne Boheme), 767, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Nude on Couch (Nacktes Mädchen auf Divan), 768, 1924/1926 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Painter and Model (Maler und Modell), 769, 1924/1927 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Nude Seated on Couch (Sitzender Akt auf Divan), 770, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Nudes in the Woods with Cat (Akte im Wald mit Katze), 771, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Black Cat (Schwarzer Kater), 772, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Black Cat (Schwarzer Kater), 773, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Standing Painter; Self-Portrait (Stehender Maler; Selbstporträt), 774, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Dutch Painter in the Studio; Jan Wiegers (Holländer Maler im Atelier; Jan Wiegers), 775, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Jan Wiegers, 776, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Self-Portrait with Pipe (Selbstbildnis mit Pfeife), 777, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Peasant Woman with Peasant Lighting his Pipe (Bäuerin mit Pfeife anzündendem Bauer), 778, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Two Peasants Conversing (Zwei Bauern im Gespräch), 779, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Drinking from the Well (Am Brunnen Trinkender), 780, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Landscape with Peasants Raking Grass (Landschaft mit Gras rechenden Bauern), 781, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Peasant Couple (Bauernpaar), 782, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Before Sunrise (Vor Sonnenaufgang), 783, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Two Women in the Woods (Zwei Damen im Wald), 784, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Croquet Players (Krokettspieler), 785, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Tango-Tea (Tangotee), 786, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Hay Harvest (Heuernte), 787, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Purple Cows in Autumn (Kühe im Herbst), 788, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Portrait of Dr. Edwin Redslob (Kopf Redslob), 789, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Ice Skater (Schlittsschuhläufer), 790, 1924/1925 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Wildboden in the Snow (Wildboden im Schnee), 791, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Mountain Slope with Yellow Trees (Bergabhang mit gelben Bäumen), 792, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - In Sertig Valley (Im Sertgital), 793, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Landscape with Houses and Horse-drawn Cart (Landschaft mit Häusern und Pferdekarren), 794, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Landscape in Spring, Sertig (Landschaft im Frühling, Sertig), 795, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Sertig Path; Sertig Valley with Clavadel Sanatorium (Sertigweg; Sertig mit Kurhaus Clavadel), 796, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Davos seen from Frauenkirch (Davos von Frauenkirch gesehen), 797, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Davos seen from Frauenkirch II (Davos von Frauenkirch gesehen II), 798, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Sertig Valley Landscape (Landschaft Sertigtal), 799, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - The Paulis (Paulis), 800, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Portrait of the Painter (Kopf des Malers), 801, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Self-Portrait (Selbstbildnis), 802, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Female and Male Head (Frauen- und Männerkopf), 803, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Three Artists; Hermann Scherer, Kirchner, Paul Camenisch (Drei Künstler: Hermann Scherer, Kirchner, Paul Camenisch), 804, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - The Three Old Women (Die drei alten Frauen), 805, 1925/1926 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Peasant Pulling a Wheelbarrow (Bauern einen Schubkarren ziehend), 806, 1925-1926/1932 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Wheelbarrow Lift in Stable (Schubkarrenaufzug im Stall), 807, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Group of Peasants; Two Peasants with Wheelbarrows on Rope-Pulley (Bauerngruppe; Zwei Bauern mit Schubkarren an Seilzug), 808, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Portrait of Manfred Schames (Porträt Manfred Schames), 809, 1925/1932 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Woman and Boy Reading in Garden (Frau and lesender Knabe im Garten), 810, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Mother with Two Children; Mrs.A. Müller and the Twins (Mutter mit zwei Kindern; Frau Müller und die Zwillinge), 811, 1925/1926 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Mrs. Albert Müller with Valley Background (Frau Albert Müller vor Bergtal), 812, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Lake Zurich (Zürichsee), 813, 1925/1932 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - In the Train; Albert Müller and Kirchner (Im Schnellzug; Albert Müller und Kirchner), 814, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Davos with Church; Davos in Summer (Davos mit Kirche; Davos im Sommer), 815, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Quarry at Wildboden (Steinbruch bei Wldboden), 816, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - House in Autumn; The Painter's House (Haus im Herbst; Haus des Malers), 817, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Clavadel in Autumn (Clavadel im Herbst), 818, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Thurgauer Sanatorium, Clavadel (Thurgauer Heilstätte, Clavadel), 819, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Sertig Valley in Autumn (Sertigtal im Herbst), 820, 1925/1926 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Lumberjacks (Holzfäller), 821, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - The Jockey Act (Jockeyakt), 822, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Three Horses (Drei Pferde), 823, 1925/1926 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Three Nude Women with Children (Drei nackte Frauen mit Kindern), 824, 1925/1932 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Bathing Women and Children (Badende Frauen und Kinder), 825, 1925/1932 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Albert Müller (Das Paar Albert Müller), 826, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - The Sinking of the Austrian Warship M.S.S. Stefan (Der Untergang des österreichischen Panzers M.S.S. Stefan), 827, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - The Mountain Demon (Der Dämon der Berge), 828, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Portrait of Wehrlin (Kopf Wehrlin), 829, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Davos Train Station (Bahnhof Davos), 830, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - Davos Dorf in Winter (Davos Dorf im WInter), 831, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - Grisons Landscape (Bündner Landschaft), 832, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - Forest in Winter (Wald im Winter; Verschneite Tannen), 833, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Ice Rink and Skaters (Eisfeld mit Eisläufern), 834, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - Farewell (der Abschied), 835, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Nude with Red Hair (Rothaarige nackte Frau), 836, 1925/1926 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Female Nude in Green, Blue, and Pink (Weiblicher Akt in Grün, Blau und Rosa), 837, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Chemnitz Factories (Chemnitzer Fabriken), 838, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - Mary Wigman's "Death Dance" (Totentanz der Mary Wigman), 839, 1926/1928 (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - Max Liebermann n His Studio (Max Liebermann in seinem Atelier), 840, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - The Frankfurt Cathedral (Der Frankfurter Dom), 841, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 186)
    - The Student (Die Studentin), 842, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 187)
    - The Rape of Helena, copy after Benozzo Gozzoli (Der Raub der Helena, Kopie nach Benozzo Gozzoli), 843, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 188)
    - The Bridge at Wiesen (Die Brücke bei Wiesen), 844, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    - White House in Sertigtal (Weißes Haus im Sertigtal), 845, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 190)
    - Street with Electric Trolley (Straße mit elektrischer Bahn), 846, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 191)
    - Women Walking with Small Dog (Gehende Dame mit Hündchen), 847, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - Street Scene with Hairdresser Salon (Straßenbild vor dem Friseurladen), 848, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 193)
    - Street Scene (Straßenszene), 849, 1926/1927 (Box 4, Folder 194)
    - Five Pedestrians (Fünf Fußgänger), 850, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - Nocturnal Street Scene (Nächtliches Straßenbild), 851, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - Street Scene at Night (Straßenszene bei Nacht), 852, 1926/1927 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Street with Passers-by under Night Lights (Straße mit Passanten bei Nachtbeleuchtung), 853, 126/1927 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Department Store in the Rain (Kaufhaus im Regen), 854, 1926/1927 (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - A Group of Artists: Otto Mueller, Heckel, Schmidt-Rottluff (Eine Künstlergruppe: Otto Mueller, Heckel, Schmidt-Rottluff), 855, 1926-1927 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - View of Dresden, Schlossplatz (Blick auf Dresden, Schloßplatz), 856, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Zurich (Zürich), 857, 1926-1927 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Wrestlers in the Mountains (Ringer in den Bergen), 858, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - Forest Clearing with Electric Lines (Berglandschaft mit elektrischer Leitung), 859, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Mountain Landscape with Electric Lines (Berglandschaft mit elektricscher Leitung), 860, 1926-1928 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Autumn Landscape with Rifle Range (Herbstlandschaft mit Scieß-Stand), 861, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - Seated Woman; Erna Kirchner (Sitzende Dame; Frau Kirchner), 862, 1926/1927 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Portrait of Dr. Ernst Gosebruch (Porträt Gosebruch), 863, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - Portrait of Mrs. Albert Müller (Bildnis Frau Albert Müller), 864, 1926/1932 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Two Nudes in the Forest II (Zwei Akte im Wald II), 865, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Student and her Friend (Studentin und Freund), 866, 1926-1927 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Skiers (Skispringer), 867, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - Head of Müller with Flowers (Müllerkopf mit Blumen), 868, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - The Violinist Häusermann I (Der Geiger Häusermann I), 869, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 214)
    - The Violinist Häusermann II (Der Geiger Häusermann II), 870, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - Davos Houses in Winter; Old Ski Jump (Davoser Häuser im Winter; Alt Sprungschanze), 871, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 216)
    - Town of Monstein Near Davos (Dorf Monstein bei Davos), 872, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 217)
    - Sleigh Ride in the Snow (Schlittenfahrt im Schnee), 873, 1927/1928 (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - Sleigh Ride (Schlittenfahrt), 874, 1927/1928 (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - Motorcycle Racers (Motorradrenner), 875, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - Bicycle Race in the Motor Relay (Radrennen mit Motorvorspann), 876, 1927/1928 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - Reclining Nude (Liegende nackte Frau), 877, 1927/1928 (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - Seated Nude in Footbath (Sitzender weiblicher Akt ein Fußbad nehmend), 878, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Nudes in the Meadows (Akte auf der Wiese), 879, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Nudes in the Forest (Nackte Frauen im Wald), 880, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 225)
    - Two Nudes in the Forest (Zwei Akte im Wald), 881, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 226)
    - Male Portrait with Cat and Wood Sculpture (Männliches Porträt mit Katze und Holzfigur), 882, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - Woman in Chair (Frau in Stuhl), 883, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 228)
    - Mother and Son (Mutter und Sohn), 884, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 229)
    - Portrait of an Old-Woman; Mrs. L. Bauer (Bildnis einer alten Frau; Frau L. Bauer), 885, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - Portrait of a White-Haired Woman; Mrs. L. Bauer (Bildnis einer weißhaarigen Frau), 886, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Before Sunrise II; Couple on the Balcony (Vor Sonnenaufgang; Paar auf dem Balkon), 887, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Portrait of Lise Gujer (Porträt Lise Gujer), 888, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - Young Artist; Hans Schiess (Junger Künstler; Hans Schiess), 889, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 234)
    - Converstation in the Garden: Hans Schiess, Lise Gujer, ad Erna Kirchner (Unterhaltung im Garten: Hans Schiess, Lise Gujer und Erna Kirchner), 890, 1927/1932 (Box 4, Folder 235)
    - Mountain Landscape from Clavadel (Berglandschaft von Clavadel), 891, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 236)
    - Mountain Forest; Forest Path in the Summer (Bergwald; Sommerlicher Waldweg), 892, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 237)
    - Clavadel in Spring (Cavadel im Frühling), 893, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 238)
    - View of Basel and the Rine (Blick auf Basel und den Rhein), 894, 1927/1928 (Box 4, Folder 239)
    - Revolution (Revolution), 895, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 240)
    - The Past; Reminiscence, Banquet Hall Project, Museum Folkwang, Essen (Die Vergangenheit; Die Errinerung, Entwurf für Festsaal, Essen), 896, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 241)
    - Genius, Banquet Hall Project, Essen (Der Genius, Entwurf für Festsaal), 897, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 242)
    - Cafe, Scene with Waitress (Cafeszene mit Kellnerin), 898, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 243)
    - Cafe (Im Cafe), 899, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 244)
    - Cafe, small Version (Cafe, kleine Fassung), 900, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 245)
    - Cafe (Kaffehaus), 901, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 246)
    - Two Women in a Cafe (Zwei Damen im Cafe), 902, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 247)
    - Dance from Laban's "Narranspiegel" (Tanz aus dem "Narrenspiegel" von Laban), 903, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 248)
    - Two Dancing Nudes (Zwei tanzende Frauenakt), 904, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 249)
    - Dance Couple (Tanzpaar), 905, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 250)
    - Two Nudes at Night (Zwei nackte Mädchen in der Nacht), 906, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 251)
    - Yellow Dancer with Grey Partner (Gelbe Tänzerin mit grauem Partner), 907, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 252)
    - Pitcher with Yellow Flowers (Krug mit gelben Blumen), 908, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 253)
    - Orchid and Inkwell (Orchidee und Tintenfaß), 909, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 254)
    - Still Life with Flowers (Blumenvase), 910, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Wineglass (Weinglas), 911, 1927-1929 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Family, Project, Folkwang Museum, Essen (Die Familie, Entwurf für Festsaal, Essen), 912, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Two Schoolgirls (Zwei Sculmädchen), 913, 1927-1929 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Boy Slinging Dart (Bube mit Wurfpfeil), 914, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Four Dark Blue Acrobats (Vier dunkelblau Akrobaten), 915, 1927-1929 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Oarsmen (Ruderer), 916, 1928/1929 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Portrait of Dr. Carl Hagemann (Bildnis Dr. Carl Hagemann), 917, 1928/1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Cafe in Davos (Davoser Cafe), 918, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Brown Figures in Cafe (Braune Figuren im Cafe), 919, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Rider with Overturned Horse (Reiterin mit gestürztem Pferd), 920, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Recumbent Cow (Liegende Kuh), 921, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Woman Walking the Street at Night (FRau geht über nächtliche Straße), 922, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Dancing Couple in the Snow (Tanzendes Paar im Schnee), 923, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Nude Woman in the Forest Meadow (Nackte Frau auf Waldweise), 924, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Two Nudes in the Forest (Zwei Akte im Wald), 925, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Playing Bathers (Spielende Badende), 926 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Dance of the Masks (Maskentanz), 927, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Sow Mountains with Skiers (Schneeberge mit Skiläufern), 928, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Sun over the Mountains (Sonne über den Bergen), 929, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Man Striding Upon Green Ground (Schreitender auf grünem Grund), 930, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Melancholy Woman (Trauriger Frauenkopf), 931, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Two Women Discussing a Man (Zwei Frauen über einem Mann sprechend), 932, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Dance Group (Tanzgruppe), 933, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Street in Twlight (Straße in der Dämmerung), 934, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Jumping Rope (Seilspringen), 935, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Brandenburg Gate, Berlin (Brandenburger Tor, Berlin), 936, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Lutzow Riverbank in the Morning (Lutzow-Ufer am Morgen), 937, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Nude in Orange and Yellow (Akt in Orange und Gelb), 938, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Dancing Nude, G. Palucca (Tanzender FRauenakt, G. Palucca), 939, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Ice Skater (Schlittschuhläufer), 940, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Ice Skater (Eisläuferin), 941, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Pair of Trotting Horses (Trabergespann), 942, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Singer at the Piano (Sängerin am Piano), 943, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Eaters (Esser), 944, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Man with Cat (Mann mit Katze), 945, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Self-Portrait with Erna (Selbstbildnis mit Erna), 946, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Lovers (Liebespaar), 947, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Color Dance I; Folkwang Museum Festival Hall Project, Essen (Farbentanz I; Entwurf für Festsaal, Essen), 948, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Moonlit Landscape (Mondlandschaft), 949, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Imaginary Nocturnal Landscape in Green and Black (Nächtliche Phantasielandschaft in Grün und Schwarz), 950, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Imaginary Meadow Flowers (Phantastische Wiesenblumen), 951, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Witch and Scarecrow in Snow (Hexe und Vogelscheuche im Schnee), 952, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Woman with Cat and Wood Sculpture (Frau mit Katze und Holzfigur), 953, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Still Life with Cat and Pipe (Stilleben mit Katze und Pfeife), 954, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Meadow Flowers and Cat (Wiesenblumen und Katze), 955, 1931/1932 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Umbrella Flowers with Newspaper and Sculptures (Blumendolden mit Zeitung und Skulpturen), 956, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - By the Davos-Platz Trainstation (Davos-Platz am Bahnhof), 957, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Town Hall, Davos Platz (Rathaus, Davos Platz), 958, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Recumbent Nude (Nackte Liegende Frau), 959, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Rushing Dancer, G. Palucca (Springende Tänzerin, G. Palucca), 960, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Twirling Dancer (Drehende Tänzerin), 961, 1931/1932 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - The Rider (Reiterin), 962, 1931/1932 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - The Organist of Spina (Der Orgelspieler von Spina), 963, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Blonde Woman in Red Dress; Portrait of Mrs. Hembus (Blonde Frau in rotem Kleid; Bildnis Frau Hembus), 964, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Two Nudes Running in the Woods (Zwei renennde Akte im Wald), 965, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Pair of Acrobats, Sculpture (Akrobatenpaar, Plastik), 966, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Three Nude Young Men; In the Stadium (Drei nackte junge Männer; Im Stadion), 967, 1932/1936 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Color Dance II; Folkwang Museum Festival Hall Project, Essen (Farbentanz II; Entwurf für Festsaal, Essen), 968, 1932-1934 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Dancing Girls in the Rays of Color (Tanzende Mädchen in farbingen Strahlen), 969, 1932-1937 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Nudes in the Forest, Small Version (Akte im Wald, kleine Fassung), 970, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Nudes in the Forest, large version (Akte im Wald, große Fassung), 971, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Sun Dancer (Sonnentänzerin), 972, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - The Couple; Self-Portrait with Erna (Das Paar; Selbstbildnis mit Erna), 973, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Ice Hockey Players (Eishockeyspieler), 974, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Hockey Players (Hockeyspieler), 975, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Hockey Players (Eishockeyspieler), 976, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Bern with Belltower (Bern mit Zeitglockenturm), 977, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Zurich, Parade Square (Zürich, Paradeplatz), 978, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Bern with Minster (Bern mit Münster), 979, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Minster Square in Bern (Münsterplatz in Bern), 980, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Campfire on August 1st (Augustfeuer), 981, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Street at Night with Illuminated Figures (Nächtliche Straße mit beleuchteten Figuren), 982, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Cafe in the Morning (Cafe im Morgen), 983, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Homage to Klee; Portrait of Paul Klee and His Wife (Hommage a Klee; Bildnis Paul Klee und Frau), 984, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Courtyard with Sunbeam (Hof mit Sonnenstrahl), 985, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Coutryard in Sunlight (Hof im SOnnenlicht), 986, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Street Trees in Basel (Basler Straße mit Bäumen), 987, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Minster in Basel (Basler Münster), 988, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Balcony Scene (Balkonszene), 989, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Holiday Procession on August 1st (Festzug am 1. August), 990, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Flowers with Sculpture, partially overpainted (Blumen mit Plastik, teilweise überstrichen), 991, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Still Life with Sculpture against Window (Stilleben mit Plastik vor dem Fenster), 992, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Ball Players (Ballspielerinnen), 993, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Archery (Bogenschützen), 994, 1935-1937 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - At the Edge of the Forest (Am Waldrand), 995, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Study of Mountain Forest (Bergwaldstudie), 996, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Mother and Child under Fir Trees (Mutter und Kinder unter Tannen), 997, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Autumn Landscape; Sertig with Clavadel Sanatorium (Herbstlandschaft; Sertig mit Kurhaus Clavadel), 998, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Cityspace; Franciscan Place in Basel (Stadtbild; Barfüßerplatz in Basel), 999, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Interior with Men; Club of the Artist Group 33 (Interieur mit Männern; Club der Künstlervereinigung Gruppe 33), 1000, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Flowers in Front of Tapestry (Blumen vor Batik), 1001, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Mountain Studio (Bergatelier), 1002, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Interior with Man and Cat (Interieur mit Mann und Katze), 1003, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Allegory (Allegorie), 1004, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Scene from "Midsummer Night's Dream" (Szene aus dem "Sommernachtstraum"), 1005, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Three Peasants (Drei Bauern), 1006, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Peasants with Picks (Hackende Bauern), 1007, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Herdsmen in the Evening (Hirten am Abend), 1008, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Peasant Woman at the Trough (Bäuerin am Brunnentrog), 1009, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Peasant Couple with Wheelbarrow (Bauernpaar mit Schubkarre), 1010, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Women Harvesting Haty (Frauen bei der Heuernte), 1011, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - The Violinist (Die Violinistin), 1012, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Landscape at Frauenkirch (Landschaft Frauenkirch), 1013, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Grisons Landscape with Sunrays (Büdner Landschaft mit Sonnenstrahlen), 1014, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Sertig Path (Sertigweg), 1015, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Mountain Forest (Bergwald), 1016, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Forst Interior (Waldinneres), 1017, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Junkerboden in the Snow (Junkerboden im Schnee), 1018, 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Fir Trees (Tannen), 1019, 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Junkerboden, 1020, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Violet House on Snow Mountain (Violettes Haus vor Schneeberg), 1021, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Woman with Goat (Frau mit Ziege), 1022, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Shepherd with Sheep (Hirte mit Schafen), 1023, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Herd of Sheep (Schafherde), 1024, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 115)